PROFESSOR: Now what we'd like to do is
we'd like to go back to our tree
search algorithm.
If you think about the tree search
algorithm we presented, it turns out
you do a lot of repeated work, because
the search tree essentially unrolls
the search graph.
And we'd like to save time by avoiding
retracing our steps, because the
second time you do the work is not going
to be any more useful than the
first time you did it.
So as a good, important general idea in
computer science, avoid repeating
work you've already done.
Now we're going to apply that in the
context of search with an idea called
graph search.
So what's up with this?
Well, let's say you have this
state graph on the left.
So the nodes are ABC and D. And from
A there's two ways to get to B. And
there's two ways to get from B to C. And
there's two ways to get from C to
D.
And so this graph is not that big.
But if you think about it, it includes
quite a lot of plans.
So the search tree, what's
it look like?
It's got A at the root.
But then it's kind of got B twice,
because there's two ways to get there.
And then under each of those
B's it's got C twice.
And it's going to be this exponential
unrolling of this graph.
And in general, this is
what happens, right?
You're going to get exponentially more
work, because when you do a search in
this tree, well, you're going to kind
of search from B at some point.
And then when that's all done, say
you're doing depth research, you're
then going to search over
here from B again.
And it's not like the second B is
going to be particularly more
informative than the first B. Now it
may be that one or the other is the
right one to do, and so we might have to
worry about which one we should do.
But we probably don't want to do both.
OK?
Because what's underneath
those trees is the same.
So let's see if we can figure out
a way to avoid repeating work.
Let's say we're doing breadth-first
search.
Well, if we do breadth-first search,
we all know what happens.
We do s.
Then we do d, e, and p.
And then we do the next layer and the
next layer and the next layer.
That means that we're going
to do this node e early.
And at some point later we're
going to do this node.
Now, breadth-first search is going to
be looking for the shallowest goal,
which I guess is here.
It's under this subtree through e.
But what about this subtree
here versus this subtree?
They're the same.
The lower one is not going to
tell you anything the higher
one didn't tell you.
And so if you're already in the process
of exploring the higher one--
let's say the higher e
is on your fringe--
there's no reason to explore both.
So you need to be careful about
which one you explore, but you
don't want to do both.
In the case of breadth-first search,
here are some nodes that we already
would have expanded.
And so we probably shouldn't expand them
again, because we're not going to
discover anything new.
How do we do this in our algorithm?
Changing the algorithm
is incredibly easy.
Understanding its consequences
is hard.
The change in the algorithm is simple.
You don't want to expand a
state twice, don't do it.
All right, so how are
we going to do that?
Well, we're going to run our tree
search, just like we always have.
There's a fringe.
There's a strategy for removing
things on the fringe.
Successors, goal tasks, none
of that has changed.
Only one small change, and that is that
every time we expand a state,
meaning we call Get Successors on it,
every time we expand a state, then we
keep track of the set we've expanded.
So that set of states we've expanded
is called the closed set.
Word of warning, lots of books and
treatments call it a closed list.
It is a closed set.
You do not want to implement
this thing as a list.
Back to the flow.
How do we implement this algorithm?
Well, we're going to do a tree search,
and we're going to keep track of the
set of states we've already expanded.
We go node by node, expanding
just like before.
But before we expand a node, we check
to make sure it's a state that we've
never expanded before.
If it is a state we've expanded before,
we've already got it covered.
We skip it.
We do not enqueue its children
onto the fringe.
Because if it's a new state,
then we do expand it.
It's very important to store the closed
set as a set, not as a list, no
matter how many people slip
up and say closed list.
The access to this is
checking membership.
Checking membership in a set is
more efficient than in a list.
And if you implement this is
a list, you will be sad.
All right, so we made a change
to our search algorithm.
Sometimes we don't expand a node.
So sometimes, rather than enqueuing
the children, we just don't.
Can this wreck the completeness
of our search.
That is, by refusing to expand certain
nodes in the tree, can we lose the
ability to guarantee that
we find a solution?
Could it be that there was one
goal and we just lost it?
Bye, bye goal.
Can that happen?
That actually can't happen, because
the only time we don't expand
something is when there's an equivalent
state in some other node
that we did expand.
So there will still be
a path to this goal.
So completeness is absolutely
unaffected by graph search.
How about optimality?
Optimality's a little trickier, OK?
Because there were these
two subtree under e.
And we know we've got one of them.
And so we know if there's a path in
one, there's a path in the other.
But maybe we got the wrong one.
Maybe we kept the wrong subtree.